Guide to the Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers MSS.249
Fales Library and Special Collections
Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers
1980-1988
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fox, Lisa
Royston, Curt
MSS.249
18 Linear Feet in 8 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 17 jewel cases, 2 film cans, and 1 flat file folder.
19 film reels
19 U-matic
17 DVDs
2 VHS
2 sound tape reels
1 audiocassette
The Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers consists of materials created by Lisa and Curt's multimedia collaborations. This collection contains reviews, photographs, transparencies, posters, video recordings, and sound recordings. Materials date from 1980 to 1988.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Lisa Fox in 2009 and 2014. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2009.249 and 2014.249.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series based on format:
Series I: Paper and Photographs
Series II: Posters
Series III: Film
Series IV: Video recordings
Series V: Sound recordings
Biographical Note
Lisa Fox was a leading dancer with the Merce Cunningham Dance Company from 1976-1980 and was a choreographer with the Lisa Fox Danse for over thirty years. Curt Royston is best known for his proficiency in a variety of media: painting, sculpture, photography, film, and video, and often in combination. His work has been shown extensively throughout the United States and Europe including a 1987 one-man exhibition at the Whitney Museum of American Art. Together Royston and Fox collaborated on a series of multimedia installations, as well as a number of 16mm dance-based films throughout the 1980s, the most popular of which is "In Artificial Light" (1983).
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Curt Royston Papers (MSS.259)
Scope and Content
This collection contains reviews, photographs, transparencies, posters, film, video and sound recordings related to the multimedia collaborations of Lisa Fox and Curt Royston. Materials date from 1980 to 1988.
Multimedia (Art).; Women choreographers.; Women dancers.; Artists -- United States.; Motion picture producers and directors.; Choreographers; Dancers; Fox, Lisa
- Series I: Paper and Photographs
  - "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reviews, 1987-88 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Transparencies, High Noon], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, transparencies, and negatives, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-20)
- Series II: Posters
  - Lisa Fox, Danse, Salle Simon I. Patino, Cite Universitaire de Geneve, February 8, [19--] (Folder 1 Right)
  - The Kitchen USA Touring, June 14-15, [19--] (Folder 1 Right)
- Series III: Film
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
    - In Artificial Light, a film by Curt Royston (2010 Restoration Print), 1982; ID: 249.0094 (Reel 249.0093, 16mm film reels Answer Print, Box Shared Fales 048, Reel 249.0094)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 20 minutes; Preservation note: Color is somewhat muddy on this print. Labwork on this old preservation job not up to standard.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Hothouse (title on print), undated; ID: 249.0001 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0001)
      Gauge: 16mm
      Length: 400 ft
    - Hothouse, 1985; ID: 249.0002 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0002)
    - Hothouse - 2nd Answer Print, undated; ID: 249.0003 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0003)
    - In Artificial Light, undated; ID: 249.0004 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0004)
      Length:700 ft
    - In Artificial Light - Mag Track, undated; ID: 249.0005 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0005)
    - Puss and Boots, c.a. 1980; ID: 249.0006 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0006)
      Length:100 ft
    - Kitchen Show on the Staten Island Ferry, c.a. 1981; ID: 249.0007 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0007)
    - Notes for an Adagio, undated; ID: 249.0008 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0008)
      Length:260 ft
    - Notes for an Adagio - Pix, c.a. 1982; ID: 249.0009 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0009)
    - White Shirt Place - Reel 1 - Mag Track, undated; ID: 249.0010 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0010)
      Length:850 ft
    - White Shirt Place - Reel 2 - Mag Track, undated; ID: 249.0011 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0011)
      Length:650 ft
    - In Artificial Light, undated; ID: 249.0012 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0012)
      Length:670 ft
    - Hot House, undated; ID: 249.0013 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0013)
      Length:450 ft
    - En Passant, undated; ID: 249.0014 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0014)
      Length:500 ft
    - Notes for an Adagio, undated; ID: 249.0015 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0015)
      Length:140 ft
- Series IV: Video recordings
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated; ID: 249.0016 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0016)
    Original format: 1in
    Duration: 33 minutes
    Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated; ID: 249.0017 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0017)
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated; ID: 249.0018 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0018, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0041)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0041.
    Original format: 3/4in Umatic
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated; ID: 249.0019 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0019)
    Original format: VHS
  - High Noon in Half Light: "Eye Light" Camera #1, November 10, 1987; ID: 249.0020 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0020, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0044)
    Duration: unknown
    General
    Alternate Title: "High Noon in Half Light"
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0044
  - Half Light "All Our Hands" Camera #1, November 10, 1987; ID: 249.0021 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0021, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0047)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0047.
  - Half Light - "Eye Light" Camera #2, November 17, 1987; ID: 249.0022 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0022, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0050)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0050
  - Half Light - "All Our Hands" Camera #2, November 17, 1987; ID: 249.0023 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0023, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0053)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0053.
  - Half Light - "Blue Room" Camera #2, November 17, 1987; ID:249.0024 (Box 4, Media ID:249.0024, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0056)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0056.
  - "Eye Light" Performance #3, November 28, 1987; ID: 249.0025 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0025, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0059)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0059.
  - "All Our Hands" Performance #3, November 28, 1987; ID: 249.0026 (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0026, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0062)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0062.
  - "Blue Room" Performance #3, November 28, 1987; ID: 249.0027 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0027, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0065)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0065.
  - Overhead Cam Performance #3, November 28, 1987; ID: 249.0028 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0028, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0068)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0068.
  - "In Artificial Light", undated; ID: 249.0029 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0029, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0071)
    Duration: 20 minutes
  - "In Artificial Light", January 1983; ID: 249.0030 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0030, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0097)
  - Downtown Madonna Part 2 and "In Artificial Light", undated; ID: 249.0031 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0031, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0074)
    Original format: Betacam SP
  - "In Artificial Light", undated; ID: 249.0032 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0032)
    Format: VHS
    Duration: [unknown]
  - "Hot House", undated; ID: 249.0033 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0033, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0077)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0077.
    Duration: 10 minutes
  - "Hot House" - Original film to video transfer, undated; ID: 249.0034 (Box 5, Media IDL 249.0034, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0080)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0080
  - Lisa Fox "Floored", Kitchen Performance 12/10/81, December 10, 1981; ID: 249.0035 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0035)
    Format: 3/4in Umatic
    Duration: 00:40:00
  - Lisa Fox "The Feast", January 1983; ID: 249.0036 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0036, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0083)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0083
    Duration: 8 minutes
  - "Lisa Fox & Rhys Chatham, Institute of Contemporary Art", January 1983; ID: 249.0037 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0037, Box Shared Fales 140, Dvd 249.0086)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0086.
  - [Untitled - Curt Royston], undated; ID: 249.0038 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0038)
- Series V: Sound recordings
  - Hot House Rough Takes, June 1985; ID: 249.0087 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0087)
    Alternate Title: Piano Takes with Harold - 6/85
  - June Mix, 6/2/82; ID: 249.0088 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0088)
  - The Bunt, The Hunt, Floored - Swiss Mix, Feb 1982, February 1982; ID: 249.0089 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0089)